Willian Belolli



williamcharllesbelolli@hotmail.com



+353 83 885 8622



linkedin.com/in/willianbelolli

Summary

I am a bilingual (Portuguese and English) professional European citizen, postgraduate in Science in Computing. I hold certificates such as ITIL Foundation and ISO IEC 20000, within 5+ years of experience in the Technology Engineer industry. I am problem solving and detailed oriented person who is always interested in learning new technologies with the expertise to troubleshooting and deal with different system architectures (ERP, Cloud, Deployment, DB).

Over the course of my career, I have worked supporting users through the phone, email, chat tools and face to face, providing exceptional support that meets their needs, training and supporting customers with invoice authorization, peripherals, scanners, tax processing, implementation of new technologies, documentation of internal resources to provide an quickly and standard support.

Being an international student, I have repeatedly been exposed to new cultures and diverse groups of people. This has made me able to quickly adapt to changes and gain a broader perspective. I keep my goals and tasks organized to maintain productivity.

I am always interested in hearing from former colleagues, managers, or just interesting professionals, so feel free to contact me if you would like to connect.

Experience



Technical Support Engineer - Cloud

Nuance Communications

Oct 2021 - Present (1 year 9 months)

- Supporting and troubleshooting distributed systems and applications such as Dragon Medical One
- DMO, Power Mic Mobile PMM, Winscribe and Speechkit. Enterprise systems as Confluence, Jira, Salesforce. Working with digital networks such as VPN's, IP, TCP, UDP, VLANs and Firewalls.
- Handling an average of 40 ticket requests monthly, offering users the best resolve, solutions, and answers to all technical inquiries. Supporting product functionality testing for server upgrades, migrations, and fail-overs on a worldwide capacity.
- Participating in remote sessions using (MS Teams, TeamViewer, LogMeIn), Troubleshooting cases with clients and partners. Communicating ad-hoc system status updates in addition to delivering them in daily/weekly handover meetings. Participation in weekly triage case meetings (Scrum), with the entire technical team.
- Contributing to technical documentation. (Knowledge Base). Product knowledge of Nuances AI, Integrated Voice Recognition, deep understanding in Adaptations Models, data packs, and Digital Chat.
- Research, analyze, document and manage resolutions to technical, operational and implementation issues related to Nuance products and their supporting technologies and infrastructures.

• Supporting in a 24x7 operational model to best help our customers and partners.

🚺 Front Desk Receptionist

Hostelworld Group

Jul 2018 - Jun 2020 (2 years)

- Managing around two hundred weekly bookings though the third part web sites, the company ones and some eventually walk-in guests.
- Greeted and welcomed an average of one hundred guests nightly on my own.
- Monitored social medias such as TripAdvisor, Booking.com, Hostelworld.com, responding customer's inquiries, reviewers providing them appropriate solution with time manner.
- Helping manager with their new staff's on-board process, training, ensuring that they are equipped with skills to meet and surpass customers' expectations and requirements.
- Ability to handle pressure dealing with people, fixing issues which occur when working in a hostile atmosphere in a satisfactory manner.

System Analyst

JS Softcom

May 2016 - Mar 2017 (11 months)

- Assisting with technical issues which also included handling an average of 120 tickets requests weekly, offering users the best resolve, solutions, and answers to all technical inquires
- Meeting people from diverse types of establishments like coffee shops, bakeries, groceries shops, gas station, pharmacies etc. I learned more about small business and closer contact with resellers technicians.
- Educating users to new models or potential clients performing product demos, or even when we had some government updates regarding taxation and charges.
- Troubleshooting our application or peripherals like printers, scanners, card machines which were connected to our solution.
- Networking this task could be accomplished through face to face, phone, email, or chat tools.
- Planning deployment projects and helped to improve our user's portfolio following the standards established by ITIL.

Computer Technician

CTIS

Apr 2015 - May 2016 (1 year 2 months)

 Working as an IT Technician to the biggest semi-public Brazilian multinational corporation in the petroleum industry, proving quality and consistently IT services to support our client and ensuring that their IT infrastructure never stops working.

- Troubleshoot Tier 1 network connectivity issues such as digital authentication, remote access, secure Wi-Fi, and wired connectivity to the internal network.
- Replacing and relocating equipment's, also managing disaster recovering (Backup's),
- Support users on mobile applications and tools within the environment including Microsoft Office Suite, Citrix, Cisco Communication tools (Webex, Jabber), and Windows OS.
- Documenting and resolving incidents in a corporate environment following processes and procedures based on ITIL concepts.



Customer Support Engineer

CISS S.A - Gestão para o Varejo

Mar 2010 - Dec 2014 (4 years 10 months)

- Working within a variety of different costumers' industry such as building shops, groceries shop, hypermarkets, pharmacies, providing technical assistance on CISS products to customers of small to giant size via phone, email and/or remote access.
- Troubleshooting system error messages and how-to separate user training session and product deficiencies.
- Documentation of issues reported and worked. Evaluating and bench marking new software that can be used to test new products released ensuring all software test meets product specifications.
- Performing deployment systems such as local databases using PostgreSQL, hardware maintenance, OS deployment.
- General networking knowledge such Firewalls, Gateways, Routing, Proxy and so on, concepts on administration of Active Directory, Domain Policy, and Group Policy.
- Ability to experience networking appliances and technologies, such as switches and Wi-Fi.
- Basic concepts as accounting bases as I had to check products taxation (Brazilian industry).

Education

cct CCT College Dublin

Postgraduate, Science in Computing 2019 - 2020

Griffith College Dublin

English Language and Literature, General 2017 - 2017



FAED UNISEP - União de Ensino do Sudoeste do Paraná

Bachelor's degree, Computer Systems Analysis 2010 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications

■XIN ITILF ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management - EXIN 5722499.20549506

EXIN S722499.20592246 IT Service Management Foundation Bridge based on ISO IEC 20000 - EXIN 5722499.20592246

Skills

Atendimento ao Cliente • Implantação de sistema • Execução de treinamento • Software corporativo • Gestão de recursos • Gestão de infraestrutura de TI • MySQL • Microsoft Excel • Cloud Computing • Cloud Development